Volodymyr Lysiuk

Email: volodymyr.lysiuk@gmail.com Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/vlysiuk

Phone: +38 097 941 91 22 Portfolio: https://vlysiuk.github.io

Career objective

Desired position: Engineering manager/RnD director/CTO

I am an experienced engineering leader with a strong technical background. I am all-in into managing complex issues and delivering high-quality products and customer value.

Being a software developer for more than 12 years, I have built a good engineering base and understanding of SDLC. For the past 7 years, I have been working as an engineering manager, managing teams from 4 to 15 people. As a manager, I enjoy empowering and inspiring people, and building strong teams and culture within the organization. I truly believe in leadership by example and think that success comes with honesty, dedication, and hard work.

Core competencies:

- Engineering: software developer for more than 12 years, building complex, high-load solutions, maintaining CI/CD and automation processes. Deep understanding of software development lifecycle, architecture design, and technology trends
- Strategic Planning and Execution: skilled in developing and implementing long-term engineering strategies aligned with business objectives. Proficient in defining technical roadmaps, setting clear goals, and executing plans to drive product development and organizational growth
- Leadership: building team environment and culture, embracing and influencing company values, leading organizational initiatives and process improvements
- People management: building the teams from scratch, team growth and motivation, leading team process, focusing on delivering results. Proven ability to recruit, mentor, and develop top engineering talent, fostering a culture of collaboration and innovation
- Project management: building and controlling delivery plans, managing resources and cost, risk and change management. Translating technical concepts into clear business objectives and building consensus across diverse stakeholders.

Professional experience

Grammarly

Engineering manager July 2021 – Present

I am leading the Billing and Payments function at Grammarly. I am responsible for driving the team charter and vision, building a scalable platform that will cover the company's consumer and B2B needs.

- Grew the team from 5 to 14 people
- Built the charter and strategy for several teams within the organization
- Led the team's split and optimized the on-call process
- Implemented the company-wide bugs monitoring process
- Redesigned the team collaboration process with the cross-functional partners

- Optimized the fraud monitoring process that saved up to \$ 300k per month
- Initiated the company incident management process

Playtika

Group manager December 2020 – July 2021

I was leading several delivery units and responsible for the quality of products that were built by my teams, proper delivery process, stakeholders, and incident management. I am also responsible for people management and growth, spreading and influencing organizational processes and culture.

Playtika

Delivery Unit Team Lead December 2019 – December 2020

My main responsibilities include project delivery from planning to deploying to production, leading and mentoring cross-functional development teams, building the proper development process and product quality, communicating with stakeholders

Global Logic

Team Lead July 2019 – December 2019

Working for the German company Zeiss. My main responsibility is to scale the existing team and build the proper development process for better team performance and predictability for the business. I am responsible for building communication between distributed teams and aligning the understanding of the project scope and client priorities

Ciklum

Scrum Master/Team Lead November 2016 – July 2019

Working for Swedish company Betsson. My responsibility is to grow motivated and high-performing professionals and support them in getting to the established goals. I am also responsible for project delivery, technical excellence, communication with product owners and architect

Ciklum

Senior software developer November 2014 – July 2019

Working for Swedish company Betsson. Developing payment system for Betsson Group services. Implementing and maintaining applications and services that require high availability and performance, working on distributed and multi-tier systems

Technical stack: .NET, C#, .NET Core, WCF, MS SQL, Javascript, NServiceBus, Rabbit MQ, Kafka, ASP.NET MVC, LINQ, EntityFramework, NUnit, Specflow, TeamCity, Jira, Git, Docker, Kubernetes

Ciklum

Senior software developer September 2010 – November 2014

Working for Swedish company Tobii (http://www.tobii.com/) Developing software for analyzing and processing eye tracking and gaze interaction data. Designing and implementing products for disabled people to help them to communicate with others

Technical stack: .NET, C#, WPF, LINQ, XML, C++, COM, SQLite, EntityFramework, NUnit, Specflow, Moq, TeamCity, Jenkins, Jira, Git, Perforce

Tikle

Senior software developer April 2008 – September 2010

Developing value-added services and content management systems for one of the biggest Ukrainian mobile operator Life. Designing and implementing operator core services related to subscriptions, campaigns, and user data. Holding technical meetings with partners Technical stack: .NET, C#, ASP.NET, WinForms, MS SQL, ADO.NET, XML, CSS, HTML, SOAP, USSD, SMPP, WAP, SVN

Tikle

Software developer September 2006 – April 2008

Developing value-added services and content management systems for one of the biggest Ukrainian mobile operator Life

Technical stack: .NET, C#, ASP.NET, WinForms, MS SQL, ADO.NET, XML, CSS, HTML, SOAP, USSD, SMPP, WAP, SVN

Kvant

Software developer April 2006 – September 2006

Developing modules for a spatial monitoring system. Implementing algorithms for object definition and correlation Technical stack: C++. MFC

NTUU "KPI"

System administrator September 2004 – April 2006

Installing and configuring software and hardware. Managing and supporting the local network. Managing user rights and access within the local domain

Education

2003–2009 NTUU "Kiev Polytechnical Institute"

Department of Applied Mathematics Faculty of Specialized Computer System

Master degree

Training Programs

April 2017 - May 2017

Name: Target Course for middle management

Description: How to manage and lead teams, motivation, and customer

collaboration

Provider: Vera Shatskaya

July 2017

Name: Time management

Description: Time management best practices

Provider: Vera Shatskaya

October 2018 - December 2018

Name: Target course for Business Leaders

Description: Introduction to finance, marketing, project management, customer

collaboration, team leading, risk management

Provider: Ciklum PM Education, Lviv Business School

January 2019 - February 2019

Name: Effective communication

Description: Cultural differences, empathy, active listening, influencing,

negotiations

Provider: Nataliya Ostashko

March 2019

Name: Sales for IT

Description: Leads generation, marketing, customer engagement

Provider: Lviv Business School

Languages

Ukrainian – native English – fluent

Certificates

Certified scrum master

PMI Agile Certified Practitioner